Atlantic States Legal Foundation; Records apap311
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Atlantic States Legal Foundation Records
1966-2009
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap311
179.74 cubic ft.
The Atlantic States Legal Foundation Records document the environmental not-for-profit organization's pollution reduction and environmental remediation projects and cases throughout the United States and territories.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of select folders in Series 1, Subseries 1 which are noted. In addition, all work product is restricted until 2029.
Acquisition Information
The Atlantic States Legal Foundation donated its records in 2009-2010 to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Atlantic States Legal Foundation, Inc. (ASLF) is a not-for-profit organization founded in 1982, with headquarters in Syracuse, New York. Since its earliest years, Samuel Sage has worked with ASLF, actively promoting numerous environmental projects and serving as president. ASLF's mission is to provide affordable technical, legal and organizational services to a variety of individuals, community groups, non-governmental organizations (NGOs), local governments and others to protect and remediate threats to the natural and human environment.
In the 1980s and 1990s ASLF used the legal frame work of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, known as the Clean Water Act (CWA) and the Emergency Planning and Right-to-Know Act (EPCRA) to ensure industrial pollution was in compliance with permits issued by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). The CWA is a federal law passed in 1976, which set water pollution standards to levels safe for human recreation. The EPCRA, passed in 1986, enabled private citizens and NGOs to request federal and state agencies documents such as, Material Safety Data Sheets, Toxic Release Inventories, SARA Title III Reports, Discharge Permits and Discharge Monitoring Reports (DMR) for individual companies. Often, the copying fees for these reports were waived for ASLF because it is a not-for-profit organization. ASLF used these reports to identify pollution discharge violations throughout the United States and U.S. Territories. After violations were identified, a sixty day notice of the intent to sue would be sent to the permit violating company. Often agreement settlements were negotiated before reaching court. The cases that did reach the courts were citizen suits and ASLF, as an organization, often needed an individual, affiliated with ASLF, in the affected area who could demonstrate harm. These individuals could provide standing for the case and were often members of ASLF or of a community group working with ASLF.
On November 28, 1990 ASLF was the first ever to settle an EPCRA citizen suit. ASLF became the leading NGO utilizing the citizen suit provision of the Clean Water Act to enforce disclosure and compliance with pollution permits. ASLF worked with local individuals and community groups, such as the Sierra Club and Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, to discover and bring legal claim against polluters. In addition to working with local groups, ASLF often worked through local attorneys in distant states, to manage the handling of a case.
In 1998 the effectiveness of citizen suits was curtailed due to a U.S. Supreme Court decision. However, ASLF's efforts forced many industries and companies to be accountable to their local communities.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials relating to the projects and cases pursued by ASLF, ASLF's collection of published environmental reports and newsletters, and subject files. ASLF activities encompassed almost every U.S. state and a few U.S. territories. The projects and cases are arranged by geographic regions, state, and finally alphabetically by the company or organization. The publications are arranged alphabetically, with separation between serial publications, New York publications, New York Department of Environmental Conservation (DEC) publications, and other publications.
The collection contains materials from the 1960s to 2000s. However the bulk of the projects were pursued in the 1980s and 1990s, items which pre- or post-date this range are often research material, DMRs or compliance reports required by consent decrees.
The collection consists of correspondence, compliance reports, discharge monitoring reports (DMR), court documents, architectural drawings, laboratory analyses, notes, news clippings, National Discharge Elimination Permit System (NPDES) permits, photographs, quarterly non-compliance reports (QNCR), remediation programs, standing, subject files, workshops and environmental newsletters, studies and research reports.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Projects, 1967-2009, Undated
Subseries 1: Midwest, 1967-2009, Undated
Subseries 2: Northeast, 1970-2009, Undated
Subseries 3: Southeast, 1977-1997, Undated
Subseries 4: Southwest, 1970-1998, Undated
Subseries 5: West, 1980-1999, Undated
Subseries 6: U.S. Territories, 1973-2004, Undated
Series 2 - Publications, 1966-2009, Undated
Subseries 1: Serials, 1971-2009
Subseries 2: New York Publications, 1966-2007, Undated
Subseries 3: New York State Department of Environmental Conservation Publications, 1966-2002, Undated
Subseries 4: General Publications, ca. 1966-2009, Undated
Series 3 - Subject Files, 1968-2004, Undated
Series 4 - Affiliate Associations, 1972-1996
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Conservation and the Environment; Environmental law--United States—Cases; Pollution--United States; Pollution--Law and Legislation--United States; Water Pollution--Law and Legislation--United States; Citizen suits (Civil procedure) -- United States; Administrative reports; Architectural drawings (visual works); Civil court records; Files by subject; Correspondence; Maps; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Notes; Pamphlets; Papers; Permits; Photographs; Serials (publications); United States. Environmental Protection Agency; New York (State). Department of Environmental Conservation; Atlantic States Legal Foundation, Inc.; United States. Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986; United States. Federal Water Pollution Control Act
- Projects, 1967-2009; Undated; 1; 118.92 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by state.
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents ASLF's numerous projects to seek compliance with pollution discharge regulations and remediation of the environment. Projects include the research into and court proceedings of companies, individuals or government officials, and a few ASLF sponsored workshops. The materials in this series contain: correspondence, compliance reports, discharge monitoring reports (DMR), court documents, drawings, intent to sue, laboratory analysis, notes, news clippings, National Discharge Elimination Permit System (NPDES) permits, photographs, quarterly non-compliance reports (QNCR), remediation programs, citizen standing and workshops. The projects are divided into subseries based on geographic regions.
  - Midwest, 1967-2009; Undated; 1.1
    This subseries documents ASLF's projects in the Midwest states, including: Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota and Wisconsin. In the Midwest ASLF sought to clean up the Great Lakes, and the Mississippi River region. The case against Koch Refining Co. in Minnesota, removed a major source of toxins in the Mississippi River and ensured compliance for many years afterwards. In Fort Wayne, Indiana, at the request of local activists ASLF researched DMRs and discovered almost a quarter of Fort Wayne industries' had a history of CWA violations.
    - Illinois - 3M Permit, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 1)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. "Analysis of the A.E. Staley/Tate & Lyle Lockout in Decatur, Illinois, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 2)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, Notes, 1988-1990; 1993-1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 3)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. DMR, Non-Compliance Reports, Permit, 1984; 1988-1991 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 4)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Facility Report, Compliance Profile, Significant Violator Report, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 5)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Newsclippings, 1995; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 6)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 1, CERCLA Preliminary Assessment Report, 1984-1986; 1990-1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 7)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 2, Application for Waste Classification, 1984; 1990-1994 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 8)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 3, Solid Waste Disposal, 1967-1970; 1972 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 9)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 4, Lafayette Plant EPA Expansion Permit, 1995; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 10)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 5, 1971-1989 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 11-12)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 6, 1975-1979 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 13-14)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 7, 1971; 1991; 1994 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 15)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Photocopy Packet 8, Essex Inc. Correspondence, 1987; 1989-1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 16)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Tate & Lyle Annual Report, Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 17)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Travel Expenses, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 18)
    - Illinois - A.E. Staley Manufacturing Co. Solidarity Notes, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 19)
    - Illinois - Abbott Laboratories Correspondence, DMR, 1995-1997; 1999 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 20)
    - Illinois - Abbott Laboratories Court Document, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 21)
    - Illinois - Acme Steel Co. Correspondence, EPA Forms, Engineer Review Notes, Permit, 1989-1990; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 22)
    - Illinois - Addison Die Casting Correspondence, Notes, Permit, 1988-1989; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 23)
    - Illinois - Addison Die Casting DMR, Baseline Monitoring Report, Laboratory Results, 1987-1989 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 24)
    - Illinois - Akzo Nobel Chemical Inc. Compliance Inspection, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 25)
    - Illinois - Allied Signal Inc. Correspondence, DMR, Notes, 1988-1990; Undated (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 26)
    - Illinois - Allied Tube & Conduit Corp. Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 27)
    - Illinois - Allstate Insurance Co. Allstate Security Sewer Drawing, 1999 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 28)
    - Illinois - Allstate Insurance Co. Correspondence, Notes, Permit, 1997-1999 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 29)
    - Illinois - Allstate Insurance Co. Engineering Service Agreement, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 30)
    - Illinois - Alpha Circuit Corp. DMR Research, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 31)
    - Illinois - American Nickeloid Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, Permit, 1987; 1989 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 32)
    - Illinois - American Steel & Wire Corp. DMR, Permit, 1986; 1989-1992; 1995 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 33)
    - Illinois - American Steel & Wire Corp. Correspondence, Notes, 1987-1988; 1990-1993 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 34)
    - Illinois - Amoco Chemical Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, DMR, Permit, 1988; 1990-1991 (Box 1 (1-Projects), Folder 35)
    - Illinois - Amoco Chemical Co. Permit, 1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 1)
    - Illinois - Amoco Oil Co.-Wood River Correspondence, EPA Forms, Engineer Review Notes, Permit, 1990; 1995 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 2)
    - Illinois - API Industries Inc., 1989 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 3)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Correspondence, Notes, 1983-1989 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 4)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 5)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Court Documents, 1987; 1991-1994 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 6-7)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. DMR, 1987-1989 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 8)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. DMR, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 9)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. DMR, 1994-1996 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 10)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Permit, 1985; 1990-1994 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 11)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Project Proposals, 1994 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 12)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Standing Questionnaire, 1990; Undated (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 13)
    - Illinois - Archer Daniels Midland Co. Storm Water Discharge Study, 1988 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 14)
    - Illinois - Argonne National Laboratory Correspondence, Notes, Permit, 1985; 1987-1990 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 15)
    - Illinois - Argonne National Laboratory DMR, 1987; 1989-1990 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 16)
    - Illinois - Atwood Acuum Machine Co. Correspondence, DMR, EPA Forms, Permit, 1987; 1990-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 17)
    - Illinois - B.F. Goodrich Co. Correspondence, DMR, EPA Form, Engineer Review, Permit, 1990; Undated (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 18)
    - Illinois - Ball-Inion Glass Packaging Corp. Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1987; 1989-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 19)
    - Illinois - Barrington Village Correspondence, DMR, Research Sheet, Permit, 1998-1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 20)
    - Illinois - Bartlett Manufacturing Inc. Company Data Sheet, Conciliation Agreement, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 21)
    - Illinois - Batavia Wastewater Treatment Facility, 1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 22)
    - Illinois - Belleville City Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1996-1997; 1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 23)
    - Illinois - Big Foot Cattle Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, Notes, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 24)
    - Illinois - Big Foot Cattle Co. DMR, EPA Forms, Permit, 1986-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 25)
    - Illinois - Bloomington/Normal Water Reclamation District DMR, Permit, 1996-1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 26)
    - Illinois - Borg-Warner Chemicals Inc. Court Documents, Permit, 1980; 1985; 1990-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 27)
    - Illinois - Borg-Warner Chemicals Inc. DMR, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 28)
    - Illinois - Bridal Originals Correspondence, DMR, Notes, Permit, 1986-1990; Undated (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 29)
    - Illinois - Burgess-Norton Manufacturing Co. Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1994-1999 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 30)
    - Illinois - Carpentersville Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 31)
    - Illinois - Cases Correspondence, Notes, 1989-1991; Undated (Box 2 (1-Projects), Folder 32-33)
    - Illinois - Cases Correspondence, Notes, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 1)
    - Illinois - Cases DMR Research Sheets, 1989; 1999; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 2)
    - Illinois - Cases Standing, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 3)
    - Illinois - Caterpillar Tractor Inc. Court Document, 1979; 1981; 1984-1985; 1987; 1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 4)
    - Illinois - Caterpillar Tractor Inc. DMR, 1989-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 5)
    - Illinois - Caterpillar Tractor Inc. Permit, 1985; 1987; 1989-1990; 1993 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 6)
    - Illinois - Circuit Systems Inc. Company Data Sheet, Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 7)
    - Illinois - Circuit World Inc. Company Data Sheet, Correspondence, 1987; 1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 8)
    - Illinois - Commonwealth Edison Co. DMR, EPA Forms, Note, Permits, 1989-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 9)
    - Illinois - Commonwealth Edison Co. Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1995-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 10)
    - Illinois - Crab Orchard National Wildlife Refuge Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1985; 1987; 1990 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 11)
    - Illinois - Danforth Corp. Comandy Data Sheet, Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 12)
    - Illinois - Dart Container Corp. DMR, Notes, Permit, 1982; 1986; 1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 13)
    - Illinois - Dean Foods Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, Notes, 1988; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 14)
    - Illinois - Dean Foods Co. DMR, Permit, 1986; 1988-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 15)
    - Illinois - Decatur Sanitary District DMR, 1997 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 16)
    - Illinois - Decatur Sanitary District DMR, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 17)
    - Illinois - Decatur Sanitary District Permit, Notes, 1996; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 18)
    - Illinois - Eagle Electronics Inc. Company Data Sheet, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 19)
    - Illinois - East Moline STP, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 20)
    - Illinois - Electro-Circuits Inc. Correspondence, Notes, 1986; 1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 21)
    - Illinois - Electronic Engineering Venture Company Data Sheet, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 22)
    - Illinois - Elgin City Correspondence, Permit, Company Data Sheet, 1996; 1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 23)
    - Illinois - Excel Corp. Correspondence, Permit, 1996-1997 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 24)
    - Illinois - Findlay Village Correspondence, DMR, Permit, Notes, 1987-1990; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 25)
    - Illinois - Forreston Cheese Company Correspondence, DMR, EPA Form, Note, 1985-1986; 1989-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 26)
    - Illinois - Fox River Water Reclamation District Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1994; 1998-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 27)
    - Illinois - General Motors Corp. Correspondence, Court Document, 1988-1990 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 28)
    - Illinois - General Motors Corp. DMR, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 29)
    - Illinois - General Motors Corp. Permit, 1981; 1986 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 30)
    - Illinois - Green Giant Co. Correspondence, Notes, 1986; 1989; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 31)
    - Illinois - Green Giant Co. DMR, Permit, EPA Forms, 1986; 1989-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 32)
    - Illinois - Hintzsche-Barnes Permit, 1995-1996 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 33)
    - Illinois - IBP Inc. DMR, Permit, 1985; 1988-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 34)
    - Illinois - Illinois Central Gulf Railroad Correspondence, DMR, Notes, Permit, 1985; 1990-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 35)
    - Illinois - Illinois Department of Corrections St. Charles Youth Center DMR, 1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 36)
    - Illinois - Illinois Mineral Co. Correspondence, EPA Form, 1986-1987; 1990-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 37)
    - Illinois - Illinois Power Co. Correspondence, EPA Form, Permit, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 38)
    - Illinois - Illinois Tool Works Inc. Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1995-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 39)
    - Illinois - Iorite Inc. Correspondence, Court Document, DMR, Notes, Permits, 1986; 1989-1990 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 40)
    - Illinois - Jade Technology Inc. Pretreatment Comprehensive Review, Notes, 1989 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 41)
    - Illinois - John Deere Foundry Permit, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 42)
    - Illinois - LaRoche Industries Inc. Correspondence, Permit, 1998-2000 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 43)
    - Illinois - LaRoche Industries Inc. DMR, Safety Data Sheet, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (1-Projects), Folder 44)
    - Illinois - Lawrence Brothers Inc. Correspondence, Court Document, DMR, Notes, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 1)
    - Illinois - Lewis University Correspondence, Court Document, Permit, 1986-1990; Undated (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 2)
    - Illinois - Lewis University DMR, 1986-1990 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 3)
    - Illinois - Libbey-Owens-Ford Co. Correspondence, Court Documents, 1986-1987; 1989-1997 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 4)
    - Illinois - Libbey-Owens-Ford Co. DMR, Permit, 1989-1990 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 5)
    - Illinois - Litchfield City DMR, Permit, 1997; 1999 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 6)
    - Illinois - Liquid Carbonic Corp. Court Document, Correspondence, Notes, DMR, 1987-1990; Undated (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 7)
    - Illinois - Lockport City Correspondence, 1996; 1999-2000 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 8)
    - Illinois - Lockport City Permit, DMR, 1996-1999 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 9)
    - Illinois - Lyon Metal Products Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1994; 1998-1999 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 10)
    - Illinois - Marathon Petroleum Co. Correspondence, Notes, 1988-1989 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 11)
    - Illinois - Marathon Petroleum Co. Court Document, 1982; 1986; 1989 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 12)
    - Illinois - Marathon Petroleum Co. DMR, 1989-1991 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 13-14)
    - Illinois - Marathon Petroleum Co. Permit, 1986; 1989 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 15)
    - Illinois - McHenry South STP Correspondence, 1997 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 16)
    - Illinois - Meadow Gold Dairies Correspondence, EPA Form, DMR, Notes, Permit, Standing, 1988-1991 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 17)
    - Illinois - Mendota Agri-Products Inc. Correspondence, EPA Forms, 1985-1986; 1988-1991 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 18)
    - Illinois - Mendota Agri-Products Inc. DMR, Permit, 1986-1990 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 19)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Sanitary District of Greater Chicago Sewage & Waste Control Ordinance, User Charge Advance, 1988 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 20)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago "A Catalyst for Toxics Use Reduction", 1991 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 21)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 22-23)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago Correspondence, Court Documents, Notes, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 24)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation Districts of Greater Chicago Fact Summary for 1988 Pass-Through Incidents (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 25)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago Laboratory Sample Analysis, 1988 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 26)
    - Illinois - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago Research and Development Department 1988 Annual Report (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 27)
    - Illinois - Midwest Solvents of Illinois Correspondence, DMR, Permit, 1985; 1989-1990 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 28)
    - Illinois - Mississippi River Transmission Corp. Correspondence, Permit, EPA Form, DMR, 1986-1990 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 29)
    - Illinois - Mitcon Corp. Correspondence, Notes, Permit, Court Document, 1986; 1989-1992 (Box 4 (1-Projects), Folder 30)
    - Illinois - Mobile Chemical Co. DMR, 1990-1991 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 1)
    - Illinois - Mobile Mining & Minerals Correspondence, Court Document, Permit, 1982; 1989-1991 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 2)
    - Illinois - Modine Manufacturing Co. Court Documents, 1986; 1989-1991 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 3)
    - Illinois - Modine Manufacturing Co. DMR, Permit, 1975; 1986; 1989-1991 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 4)
    - Illinois - Moline-North Slope STP DMR, Permit, 1999 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 5)
    - Illinois - Morton International Inc. Permit, Comments, 1996 (Box 5 (1-Projects), Folder 6)